Inventory of the Papers of Duke and Duke 1854-1956
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Inventory of the Papers of Duke and Duke 1854-1965
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 79-6
This collection consists of 232 boxes.
This collection documents the work of the Duke and Duke law firm of Charlottesville, Virginia, from 1854-1956 and includes correspondence, case files, legal documents and financial records relating to the practice.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Richard Thomas Walker Duke, son of Richard and Maria Walker Duke, was born on June 6, 1822 in Charlottesville, Virginia, where he spent his childhood. After attending private schools, he entered Virginia Military Institute and finished second in the class of 1845. Upon graduating he taught school in Lewisburg, Virginia (now West Virginia) but returned to Charlottesville when his father died in 1849, and began studying law at the university. In 1850 he started his own law practice and over the next ten years built a law office, was chosen one of Charlottesville's first aldermen, served briefly as mayor, and became Commonwealth's attorney. He married Elizabeth Scott Eskridge of Staunton, and they had two sons, William and R.T.W., Jr. (Tom), and a daughter, Mary, who lived to adulthood; two other children died in childhood.
As colonel of the 48th Regiment of the Virginia Volunteers, R.T.W. Duke took an active role in the Civil War. In 1864 he resigned his commission because of a dispute with a superior officer but re-enlisted thirty days later. He surrendered with his troops at Silas Creek in 1865 and returned to his law practice and position as Commonwealth's attorney. From that time on Duke was known as "the Colonel," and in honor of his service in the recent war, the local camp for the Sons of Confederate Veterans was named for him.
In 1863 Duke bought Sunnyside, a 70-acre tract of land northeast of Charlottesville (on which the Law School is now located), and farmed this property until his death. He was chose secretary/treasurer of the Board of Trustees of the Samuel Miller Fund established in 1869. In 1870 Duke assumed the fifth district's Congressional seat for two terms as a member of the Conservative party. Lobbying for a strong South throughout his term, Duke actively opposed the 14th Amendment. R.T.W. Duke died after a lingering illness in the summer of 1898.
William R. Duke, born in 1849, possessed his father's farming instincts and commitment to political involvement. Together they farmed and resided at Sunnyside, whose ownership William shared with his brother Tom after their father's death. Although William studied law at Virginia and in 1883 joined his father's law practice, he devoted more energy to farming and such groups as the Virginia Cattlemen's Association. In 1897 he was elected delegate to the Virginia General Assembly. Like his father, William was also involved in local affairs, serving, for example, as clerk of the Miller Fund Board of Trustees for many years. William died in 1929 and was survived by his sons, William (Billy) and Camman.
Since he was born in 1853, Richard Thomas Walker Duke, Jr. (Tom) witnessed the Civil War during his impressionable boyhood years and later wrote about those experiences. A gifted writer and student of languages, Tom studied classics, French, German and English literature when he entered the University of Virginia in 1870. He was awarded the Thomas Jefferson Prize for the best essay in 1872 and then turned his attention to the study of law in 1873-74. It is likely that he later read law for a time in his father's office before passing the bar. Although the practice of law became his career, Duke wrote prose and poetry the rest of his life and was published in the New York Herald and such magazines as Century, Lippincott's, and Illustrated American.
Throughout his long career Tom was active in town, university, and state affairs. Among the organizations in which he held office were the Masons, Zeta Psi fraternity, the Sons of the American Revolution, the Sons of Confederate Veterans, the Miller Board, the U.Va. Alumni Association, and the state Democratic Committee. He served from 1886 to 1901 as judge of the Corporation Court (now called the Circuit Court), as Commonwealth's attorney from 1916 to 1920, and as a member of the Committee to Revise the Virginia Code in 1908. In addition he sat on the boards of a variety of corporations, including the Charlottesville Ice Company, the First National Bank, and a number of Kentucky and West Virginia coal development companies in which his family had invested. From 1907 to 1910 Tom edited the Virginia Law Journal.
Tom Duke married Edith Ridgeway Slaughter in 1884, and they produced six children of whom five grew to maturity: Mary, R.T.W. III (Walker), John Flavel Slaughter (Jack), William Eskridge, and Helen Risdon. He built a spacious home for his family at 616 Park Street. A frequent traveller because of his practice, Duke also travelled for pleasure. As the children grew up, Edith often accompanied him to New York or Washington to shop, visit friends and attend plays, or she took journeys alone to visit children and other relatives. All the Duke children, as they reached their teens, attended boarding school, and all received at least some college education. Edith Duke died suddenly in 1921, and two years later, Tom married Maymee Richardson Slaughter, his wife's sister-in-law from Lynchburg. In March of 1926 Tom died at the age of 76.
Walker, after a few years in the Navy, joined the Army and became a career officer. Jack served in the Army during World War I and then began a career in business. In 1917 Eskridge took a law degree at Virginia and joined his father's practice. He was plagued by ill-health throughout his career, and soon after their father's death, his sister Mary, a former social worker, began assisting in the law office. Helen, a librarian, worked in New York and Norfolk for a year or so before moving back to the family home. Eskridge and his wife, Lucy Lee, had three children of whom two, William Eskridge, Jr. (Bill) and Lucy Marshall, grew to adulthood. Jack died in 1933; Eskridge, in 1959; Walker, in 1960; Mary, in 1966; and Helen, in 1984.
The Charlottesville law practice established by R.T.W. Duke in 1850 remained in the family for two succeeding generations. After studying law with John B. Minor at the University of Virginia, Duke practiced alone until 1858 when he built his office at 20 Court House Square and took James D. Jones as a partner. Another lawyer, Louis G. Hanckel, joined the firm in the early seventies and handled insurance business. When Tom finished his legal studies in 1874, he assisted his father whose partner by then was Stephen V. Southall. In the 1880's the firm was called Duke and Duke, William having joined his father shortly before Tom became judge.
The early work of the firm was limited to real estate, debt collection, and probate work, with an occasional criminal case. In addition, there was ample time for all three lawyers to pursue their assorted outside interests. At the office each man wrote his own letters, Tom switching to a Remington typewriter in 1889, before the days when they could hire a stenographer. The Dukes handled property rentals for some of their clients, the wealthiest and best known of whom was Jefferson Levy, owner of Monticello, the Opera House and a great deal of other property in town.
With the combination of "the Colonel's" death, the social and economic changes in town around the turn of the century, and the energetic leadership of Tom, the workload of the practice increased and became more diverse. Loan and bond operations were added to the civil and criminal work and property management. Around 1917 Eskridge and Clarence E. Gentry joined the firm, now called Duke, Duke and Gentry. The law office was torn down in 1922, and the firm moved to a building shared with other lawyers at the corner of Fifth and Jefferson Streets. The practice flourished, and the Dukes often hired Virginia law students or graduates as clerks or associates, including Elizabeth Tompkins (the first female graduate of the Law School), Bernard Chamberlain, Anna Dinwiddie and John Yancy.
It has not been determined whether the Dukes sold insurance after Hanckel left, but some time after Eskridge joined the firm in the late teens, the Insurance Agency was established. The title was changed to the Insurance Agency of Charlottesville in 1923 when W.F. Carter, Jr. as agent. After Carter misappropriated funds, he was relieved of his job, the agency was incorporated, and the Dukes' interest in the business was eventually bought out by William B. Murphy.
Eskridge carried on the law practice with the assistance of Mary and an occasional associate. In 1937 he wrote that his firm "is regional and local counsel for a number of insurance companies, Virginia counsel for the Pike Coal Company, and does a general legal business, specializing in insurance, real estate, corporation and probate law, also maintains a collection department." With his failing health in the late forties, the practice dwindled until 1955 when Duke and Duke closed, a little over a hundred years after it began.
Scope and Content Information
The Duke law firm papers in 232 boxes (108.5 linear ft.) dating from 1854-1956 provide extensive documentation of a small-town family practice. Since the insurance business and the Dukes' family business affairs were handled in the same office as the law practice, these files have remained with the legal files. The family correspondence found with these papers was transferred to Special Collections in Alderman Library. The collection documents in detail the activities in this law office for a hundred years.
The firm papers were transferred from the first law office to the second and on to the Park Street home where they apparently were shifted more than once. Things were thus unavoidably jumbled, but the order within cartons, the types of file boxes and folders, and the dates made it possible, for the most part, to reconstruct the original filing arrangements.
This collection is rich in source material for scholars of legal, social or local history. The first, most obvious area of research is the changes in the character of this small-town law practice from the post- Civil War to the post-World War II periods. Well documented are the shifts in the type of legal work the firm handled, the daily office operations over the years, the economic vicissitudes of the practice, and the attitudes of three generations of lawyers. There is also a good deal of information on the political, economic and social conditions of the Charlottesville area during the time span of the Dukes' practice.
Organization
The papers are organized into eight series: the first six concern the law practice; the seventh, the insurance business; and the eighth, family business.
Series I. Incoming letters (boxes 1-43) -- From 1869 to 1923 (and occasionally through the 1940's) incoming letters were filed separately from other material. From 1899 to 1923 all incoming letters were stored annually in special file boxes arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name. The papers in this series are arranged as they were found.
Series II. Copies of outgoing letters (boxes 44-57) -- From the 1870's through the teens copies of outgoing letters were kept chronologically in letterpress books. The books are stored in chronological order.
Series III. Case files (boxes 58-125) -- The case files date back to 1874 but are concentrated between 1920 and 1955. While the dates of these case files overlap the chronological ones described above, case files were by no means regularly created until the early twenties when the other system was virtually abandoned. Since many but not all of the case files were numbered, it was impossible to restore them to numerical order. Therefore, they have been grouped into decades and then arranged alphabetically by title found on the original folder. If the original folder was numbered, that number is noted on the new one. The cases concern principally the settlement of debts, property and divorce, as well as, for the last few decades, insurance claims.
Series IV. Legal documents (boxes 126-145) -- These documents, originally stored apart from case files, are organized chronologically according to type of document, the largest groups of which are deeds (1885- 1929) and titles (1876-1936). Also included in this series are documents related to specific cases (ca. 1870-1925), to the coal business, and to miscellaneous matters (ca. 1800-1950).
Series V. Financial papers (boxes 146-167 and oversize) -- The financial papers were likewise apparently filed separately in the office. They include notes, bonds, collections, accounts, bills, taxes, etc. and are arranged alphabetically (ca. 1870-1950). Ledgers containing the same sort of financial records are organized by size.
Series VI. General office correspondence and cases (boxes 168-185) -- This alphabetical file, ca. 1920-1955, was apparently created for routine correspondence concerning clients and office matters. For some reason certain cases were also incorporated into the alphabetical system, despite the fact that numbered case files continued to be created until the practice closed. (To complicate matters a bit further, there seem to have been two alphabetical files used consecutively. These have now been merged into one.) This series contains correspondence and case files, desk diaries, memoranda, unfiled office papers, and files relating to the insurance companies Eskridge represented.
Series VII. Insurance agency files (boxes 186-217) -- These files of the Insurance Agency of Charlottesville, 1923-1927, cover the period in which W.F. Carter, Jr. was agent. At the beginning of the series are documents concerning the audit of the agency and the subsequent incorporation.
Series VIII. Family business files, civic material and miscellany (boxes 218-232) -- These records dating from the 1880's provide a good deal of information about the financial affairs of the Charlottesville Dukes as well as their relatives.
Contents List
- Incoming Letters
  - Incoming Letters 1869-1885, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Incoming Letters 1890-1899, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Incoming Letters re Ohio and Big Sandy Coal Co. 1899 Oct. 31-1900 May 18, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Incoming Letters, A-L 1900 Oct.-Dec, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Incoming Letters, M-Z 1900 Oct.-Dec, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Incoming Letters 1900-1901 (Box 4)
  - Incoming Letters, A-Z 1900 Dec. 31-1901 Mar. 31, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Incoming Letters, A-D 1901 Jun. 5-Aug. 8 (Box 4)
  - Incoming Letters, E-Z 1901 Jun. 5-Aug. 8, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Incoming Letters, A-Z 1901 Dec. 13-1902 Feb. 5 (Box 5)
  - Incoming Letters, A-Z 1902 Sept. 1-Dec. 31, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters 1902-1903 (Box 6)
  - Incoming Letters, A-C 1902 Dec. 31-1903 Mar. 31 (Box 6)
  - Incoming Letters, H-Z 1902 Dec. 31-1903 Mar. 31, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1903 Mar. 11-Jun. 15, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1903 Jun. 12-Aug. 29, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1903 Aug. 22-Dec. 24, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1904 Jul. 4-Oct. 1, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters 1904-1905 (Box 9)
  - Incoming letters, A-J 1905 Jul. 31-Nov. 1, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Incoming Letters, K-Z 1905 Jul. 31-Nov. 1, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1905 Nov. 1-Dec. 31, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Incoming letters re Ohio and Big Sandy Coal Co., A-Z 1905 Dec. 31-1906 Sept. 1, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Incoming letters re Ohio and Big Sandy Coal Co., I-Z 1905 Dec. 31-1906 Sept. 1, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Incoming letters re Ohio and Big Sandy Coal Co. 1906 Oct. 1-1907 Aug. 22 (Box 11)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1906 Jan. 1-Mar. 31, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1906 April 6-Jun. 31, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Incoming letters, A-K 1906 Jul. 1-Oct. 2, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Incoming letters, L-Z 1906 Jul. 1-Oct. 2, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters 1906-1907 (Box 13)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1907 Ju. 1-Sept. 30, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Incoming letters, A-C 1907 Sept. 30-Dec. 31 (Box 13)
  - Incoming letters, D-Z 1907 Sept. 30-Dec. 31, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1907 dEC. 30-1908 Feb. 29, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1908 April 29-Jul. 14, 4 folders (Box 15)
  - Incoming letters, A-R 1908 Jul. 15-Sept. 30, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Incoming letters, S-Z 1908 Jul. 15-Sept. 30 (Box 16)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1908 Oct. 1-Nov. 30, 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Incoming letters, A-C 1908 Dec. 1-1909 Jan. 31 (Box 16)
  - Incoming letters, D-Z 1908 Dec. 1-1909 Jan. 31, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1909 Feb. 1-Mar. 31, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1909 Apr. 1-Jun. 18, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1909 Jun. 18-Aug. 31, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1909 Sept. 1-Dec. 1, 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters 1909-1911, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1912 Jan.-Feb., 4 folders (Box 21)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1912 Mar.-May, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1912 Jun.-Aug., 4 folders (Box 22)
  - Incoming letters, A-M 1912 Dec. 1-1913 Feb. 19, 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Incoming letters, N-Z 1912 Dec. 1-1913 Feb. 19, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1913 Feb. 19-May 1, 4 folders (Box 23)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1913 May 1.-Jul. 1, 4 folders (Box 24)
  - Incoming letters, A-Q 1913 Jul. 1-Nov. 1, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Incoming letters, R-Z 1913 Jul. 1-Nov. 1 (Box 25)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1914 Feb. 1-May 1, 4 folders (Box 25)
  - Incoming letters, A-C 1914 May 7-Aug. 1 (Box 25)
  - Incoming letters, D-Z 1914 May 7-Aug. 1, 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1914 Aug. 1-Dec. 1, 4 folders (Box 26)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1915 Feb. 1-Apr. 8, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1915 Apr. 8-Jun. 21, 4 folders (Box 27)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1916 Nov. 1-1917 Jan. 1, 4 folders (Box 28)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1917 Jan. 1-Mar. 17, 5 folders (Box 28)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1917 mar. 17-May 25, 6 folders (Box 29)
  - Incoming letters, A-B 1917 May 25-Aug. 27 (Box 29)
  - Incoming letters, C-Z 1917 may 25-Aug. 27, 6 folders (Box 30)
  - Incoming letters, A-H 1917 Aug. 27-Nov. 3, 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Incoming letters, I-Z 1917 Aug. 27-Nov. 3, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1917 Nov. 1-1918 Jan. 1, 3 folders (Box 31)
  - Incoming letters, A-J 1918 Jan. 1-Apr. 1, 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Incoming letters, K-Z 1918 Jan. 1-Apr. 1, 3 folders (Box 32)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1918 Apr. 1-Jul. 1, 4 folders (Box 32)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1918 Oct. 8-Dec. 24, 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1919 May 1-Aug. 30, 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1919 Aug. 30-1920 Jan. (Box 34)
  - Incoming letters, A-K 1920 Jan. 1-May 1, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Incoming letters, L-Z 1920 Jan. 1-May 1, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1920 Jul. 1-Nov. 26, 4 folders (Box 35)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1920 Jul. 1-Nov. 26, 4 folders (Box 35)
  - Incoming letters, A-D 1920 Nov. 26-1921 Mar. 1 (Box 35)
  - Incoming letters, E-Z 1920 Nov. 26-1921 Mar. 1, 3 folders (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters 1910-1920 (Box 36)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1921 mar. 1-Jul. 1, 4 folders (Box 36)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1921 Jul. 1-Oct. 3, 4 folders (Box 37)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1921 Oct. 3-1922 Jan. 4, 4 folders (Box 37)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1922 Apr. 14-Jul. 1, 4 folders (Box 38)
  - Incoming letters, A-J 1922 Jul.-Oct., 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Incoming letters, K-Z 1922 Jul.-Oct., 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1922 Oct. 4-1923 Feb. 23, 4 folders (Box 39)
  - Letters from T. Irving Hadden 1923-1933, 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Incoming letters, A, B, S-T 1923-1929, 4 folders (Box 40)
  - Incoming letters of R.T.W. Duke, Jr., A-Z 1924 Jan.-Jul., 4 folders (Box 40)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z 1924, 3 folders (Box 41)
  - Incoming letters, A-Z for R.T.W. Duke Jr., 1925-1926, 3 folders (Box 41)
  - Incoming letters, B, C, D, G, H, L, P, S, T 1927-1928 (Box 41)
  - Incoming letters, A-M 1929-1930, 3 folders (Box 41)
  - Incoming letters, N-Z 1929-1930, 7 folders (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters 1920's, 3 folders (Box 42)
  - Incoming letters 1930 Apr.-May (Box 42)
  - Incoming letters 1933 Jul.-Dec. (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters 1930's (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous incoming letters 1940's, 4 folders (Box 434)
- Letterpress Books
  - Letterpress Book 1875 Feb. 1-1888 July 25, 4 books (Box 44)
  - Letterpress book 1888 July 25-1891 Nov. 1, 3 books (Box 45)
  - Letterpress book 1891 Nov. 17-1895 Oct. 28, 4 books (Box 46)
  - Letterpress book 1895 Jan. 31-1896 Aug. 15, 3 books (Box 47)
  - Letterpress book 1896 Aug.-1897 Sept. 14, 3 books (Box 48)
  - Letterpress book 1897 Sept. 15- 1899 Sept. 22, 3 books (Box 49)
  - Letterpress book 1899 June 21-1901 May 28, 3 books (Box 50)
  - Letterpress book 1901 Mar. 11-1904 Mar. 17, 3 books (Box 51)
  - Letterpress book 1904 Mar. 17-1907 Jul. 11, 3 books (Box 52)
  - Letterpress book 1906 Aug. 24-1909 Sept. 23, 4 folders (Box 53)
  - Letterpress book 1909 Sept. 23-1912 Apr. 22, 3 books (Box 54)
  - Letterpress book 1912 Apr. 22-1914 Jul. 18, 3 books (Box 55)
  - Letterpress book 1914 Jul. 14-1917 Jan. 26, 3 books (Box 56)
  - Letterpress book 1917 Jan. 26-1919 Jul. 11, 4 books (Box 57)
- Case Files
  - 1850's--1870's
    - Harris v. Maxwell 1874-1881 (Box 58)
    - Charlotte Isabella Holmes 1854-1898 (Box 58)
    - Lilly v. Moseley 1877-1882 (Box 58)
    - Lowell v. Percy 1869-1871 (Box 58)
    - Thurman v. Thurman 1872-1892 (Box 58)
    - Virginia State Senate Journal re C& O Railroad 1867-1888 (Box 58)
    - J.C. Walker 1871-1893 (Box 58)
  - 1880's
    - Brown v. Brown 1886 (Box 58)
    - J.G. Bullock's Trust Fund 1882-1890 (Box 58)
    - Estate papers for R.S. Alvis, J.L. Batchelder, Mary S. Brown, William Durrett, J.L. Gianniny, S.G. Goodman, R.M. Maupin, John T. Walton 1884-1914 (Box 58)
    - Everett v. Everett 1880-1897 (Box 58)
    - Faber v. Harris 1886-1896 (Box 58)
    - Jaurier v. Macgruder 1885-1890 (Box 58)
    - G.T. Mahanes 1880's-1890's (Box 58)
    - Martin v. Martin 1880's (Box 58)
  - 1890's
    - Lizzie Gill Thurman 1898-1913, 1928 (Box 58)
    - J.J. Bowcock v. Beck 1890 (Box 59)
    - J.F. Caldwell 1897 (Box 59)
    - Chapman v. Woods 1897-1898 (Box 59)
    - H.P. Clarke c. 1890 (Box 59)
    - Duke v. Kent 1898-1906 (Box 59)
    - Duke & Duke v. Massie 1899-1902 (Box 59)
    - N.P. Farrar 1892 (Box 59)
    - B.F. Ficklin's Estate 1891-1904, 2 folders (Box 59)
    - Gleason v. Warner Elevator Mfg. Co. 1896-1987 (Box 59)
    - Goodman v. Goodman 1896-1899 (Box 59)
    - Gordan Land Co. 1890's (Box 59)
    - Hamilton v. Hamilton 1895 (Box 59)
    - C.H. Harman's Estate 1899-1910 (Box 59)
    - E.J. Lee's Executors 1897-1920's (Box 59)
    - Levy land administration; Lee estate acquisition 1892-1913 (Box 59)
    - F. L. Longfield 1891 (Box 59)
    - Peyton v. Gilbert 1898-1913 (Box 59)
    - Powers v. Powers 1890-1902, 5 folders (Box 60)
    - Robinson v. Robinson 1895-1901 (Box 60)
    - Sneed v. Thomas 1890 (Box 60)
    - Silas Walker 1896-1899 (Box 60)
    - Thomas H. Walker 1892-1910 (Box 60)
    - Thomas Wallace 1894 (Box 60)
    - West Virginia v. Reed 1890 (Box 60)
    - Whiting v. Vaughn & Luck 1890 (Box 60)
    - T. E. Wilhoit, W.R. Duke, trustee 1895-1906, 1927-1930, 2 folders (Box 60)
    - Wills Trustees v. Wills Creditors 1890 (Box 60)